Netflix, Meta, and TikTok. You're
interviewing for a company, like
literally never say that. The goal isn't
to be [music] as good as a native. The
goal is to be as good as the next
executive. Weather, sports, family,
[music] it's like all boring. To be
better at business English, listen to
the
>> Hi everybody. My name is Sora Lee. I go
by Sora Unnie online, and I started my
channel to share everything I've learned
since the young days. So you don't have
to repeat the same mistakes and you can
grow and scale faster. What jobs? I have
a few jobs. I'm a founder and CEO of a
marketing agency called Curated Agency
with a K. We work with the largest
Korean beauty brands. I also started a
women's wellness brand called Hustlin'
Heart. We hope to make products to
support women's wellness journey
throughout their lives.
>> I actually got to know you first, of
course, because of Dolsing Singles. I
watched the show and you made such an
impression on me because I felt like you
were so authentic and always stayed true
to yourself. How was your experience on
the show and did it impact your career
or life at all?
>> Yeah, it was super therapeutic to be on
the show cuz honestly, I don't get to
see many Korean American people who are
divorced. We understand both cultures,
like how divorce is perceived in America
versus how it's perceived in Korea and
dealing with the Asian parents, the
Korean parents, and the stigma and all
the challenges that come with being
divorced person in Korea and you know,
also being single parents. So having
that community of like Unnie and Oppas
now and who can help me navigate that
has been really incredible experience.
The filming itself was took about eight
days, was super therapeutic for me
because there was a lot of things that I
hadn't fully processed at the time. Like
having like doing the confessional and
really being forced to face my emotions
and all the hardships helped me heal
faster in an accelerated way. So I'm
really grateful for the opportunity.
>> That's so great. I'm I'm to hear that.
So you mentioned you are running two
companies now. Before that, what career
path
>> Um I was in big tech in product
marketing, product strategy function for
the past 13 years at Netflix, Meta, and
TikTok. And most recently, I was the
global head of product marketing for
creative solutions for TikTok. So, I
worked on making sure advertisers
understand the best practices when it
comes to creative and building products
to support those goals and doing sales
enablement globally.
>> You've done so much in your career.
That's really amazing. What are some of
the hardships that you've faced as an
entrepreneur?
>> Without having some sort of financial
security, I think it could be a lot more
stressful, but I chose this path because
it's more fulfilling and rewarding for
me. I want to be in a situation where I
could make no money or a lot of money,
like high-risk, high-reward situation
versus having the same salary. But, I do
miss having Meta insurance. It was
really nice.
>> You moved to the US when you were how
old?
>> I'll tell you my whole journey. So, my
mom sent me to Vancouver, Canada at like
an English camp for 3 weeks when I was
in 6th grade. I did the same thing in
New Zealand for 6 weeks the next year,
and I did something very similar in
Australia, I want to say for 2 weeks.
>> Mhm.
>> And people say, "Oh, spending that kind
of money during short period of time in
these countries is a waste of money."
But, I really think it depends on the
child.
>> Mhm.
>> I've always been very ambitious. I
always wanted to see how far I could go.
I don't think it works well if a child
is not interested, but parents are
pushing. I tutored over like 30 kids in
when I was in college to make money for
tuition. It's very obvious for kids who
don't care. No amount of money will save
them. So, I care more about motivating
them and why it's important for them to
learn. So, that's what those trips did
for me exactly. So, if I spoke this one
language, the whole world opens up. I am
no longer required to just be in Korea
and look for employment opportunities or
love interest just in one small tiny
country.
>> Mhm.
>> So, that's what motivated me when I came
back I would study harder and look for
ways to actually improve English, not
just get better grades, which I think is
a key difference cuz I wanted to speak
well and make friends. You know, I want
to be popular if I were to move to
America. I didn't want to just be good
at English.
>> what I mean? So, then I moved to America
when I was 16 and then I finished high
school in Cincinnati, Ohio.
>> Okay.
>> Which I chose on purpose. I actually
think that going to LA or New York as a
very extroverted person
>> Mhm.
>> would not have been good for me. I would
have started drinking earlier or hanging
out with friends, just wasting money and
time
>> Uh-huh.
>> when I should be studying. In Ohio, it
was very wholesome. Like I went to
Catholic school. Everyone was so nice.
There were only like two or three Asian
people in my school.
>> Do you remember any moment where it was
like really difficult for you?
>> the word um r l like girl
>> Uh-huh.
>> world
>> It's very hard for Koreans to pronounce.
>> Mhm.
>> So, I remember in high school in our
senior year we do this yearly trip
called Kairos and in one of the rooms I
was just saying like I don't I just
can't pronounce it. So, it was like
bunch of girls and like girl, you know,
they're like, you know, saying it with
me until I got it. I just like have that
memory of, you know, world and girl is
so hard to say. But I I did work a lot.
Like let's say we had to read Tom Sawyer
or whatever of Huckleberry Finn. I would
read in English and in Korean and
SparkNotes and in English again. So, I
would read the same thing multiple times
until I finally got it. So, it was a lot
of work on my end to make sure that I
was understanding everything.
>> Wow. I can't say the same for myself
when I was in high school. That's for
sure. [laughter]
>> The goal isn't to be as good as a
native.
>> Mhm.
>> The goal is to be as good as the next
executive. So, to not only speak
English, but also speak English at a
very very high level. I did a number of
things.
>> Mhm.
>> And there's a few things I would
recommend to be better at business
English. I would say listen to the
earnings call.
>> Mhm.
>> If you're working for a public company,
your CEO does earnings calls or earnings
press release regularly.
>> Mhm.
>> I would listen to it multiple times at
different speeds sometimes to make sure
I'm understanding every single word
correctly. You're learning a few things
there. How do executives speak?
>> Mhm.
>> How does Wall Street speak in a
financial manner? Like what are the
priorities for the company? How are they
evaluating? This is actually a really
good tip if you're interviewing for a
company, especially for a senior
position. You reference like in Doc's
most recent earnings calls, he mentioned
this thing.
>> Wow.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And this is why I want to work with this
team.
>> Got you.
>> Which would set you apart from all the
other candidates. You don't want to work
at Meta cuz it's a cool company. It'll
be a good for my resume. Like literally
never say that.
>> Um.
>> Or if you have VPs and directors are
going to have things called all hands or
even smaller companies CEOs are going to
have all hands where they talk about all
the great things that they've done. What
are the goals for the next quarter? If
those things are recorded, I would
especially if you're learning English
and getting a hang of your new job as
well, I would listen to that multiple
times. I also in my spare time, I rarely
watch TV other than I've been watching
So I Young YouTube. Anyways, I rarely
watch TV, but when I do watch TV, it
would be for something that I could
learn.
>> Mhm.
>> I would watch things like Suits or House
of Cards, The West Wing, How to Get Away
With Murder. And if I like certain
phrases from those TV shows or any sort
of like executive calls, I write them
down in my notes and I try to use them
within the same week in real situation.
>> You give yourself a deadline kind of.
>> Yeah. So I try to use them at least
three times so then it's part of my
vocabulary.
>> Wow.
Do you think grammar is like very
important to be able to communicate with
people in a daily basis in the US?
>> Grammar is still important, but But do
think that Koreans over index on
grammar. Having the idea matters more.
To be honest, just because you speak
English doesn't make you smart. Like you
need to have the material. So like on
the other hand, when you know your
stuff, don't feel like you're going to
sound stupid because your English is not
perfect. Have confidence cuz I think
Koreans always like oh like where's the
subject and the verb? Like always like
forming sentences in their head. But
actually memorizing things is super
helpful. So in the when I was younger, I
just memorized the entire Mulan and The
Truman Show. If you do that, then
sentences just come out of your mouth
without having to like form them in your
head. So watch something that's like
uplifting, not a lot not a lot of cuss
words, or like rom-com or just like
lifestyle things. So that's why I
thought The Truman Show was a really
good one. Or Friends is a good one. And
I would also do something called
shadowing. Whenever they're speaking,
like say the same thing right after and
like really act. Don't just like
monotonously read what they're saying,
but like act like you're doing some like
really like really mimicking them. And I
used to have this Sony recorder where
I'm like recording myself speaking
English and then I can hear my mistakes.
So those things are helpful. I think
Koreans avoid small talk, but it's
really important actually. I used to
think that I have to watch sports just
to fit in. Be who you are and I think at
work, especially if you're a Korean
person working in America, like there's
so much interest in Korean culture,
Korean skin care, K-pop. So if they're
interested, like you can talk about
that. Or like if someone asks you what's
your favorite K-beauty product, like go
all in on it. Like leaning into who you
are and I think it's actually helpful
cuz people want to hear. Typical like oh
how is the weather when you went there?
Like that's boring. But I think oh we
had a Chuseok festival this weekend. Oh
what is that? Korea used to be an
agricultural country and we celebrate
harvest and we do these things. That's
so much more interesting. Small talk
doesn't need to be the same thing, you
know, we can think it's like weather,
sports, family. It's like all boring.
But I think um going one layer deeper, I
think is also helpful.
>> I think you're very motivated,
confident, and enthusiastic person. I
just like one of the words that come
from and then how do you maintain it
after you achieved so much, too?
>> Mm, okay. So, my mom and my both my
grandmothers are such big inspiration to
me. Like, for example, my paternal
grandma gave birth to a stillborn
because she's had to cut wood to sell in
the market. She was doing that like the
day before she gave birth because they
were that poor. And when I look at my
mom, also, like she's super hard working
and if she had been born a male, I think
she her life would have turned out so
differently. But, I have the
opportunities that they didn't have and
it was really my mom who really fought
hard for me to study abroad even though
my parents are not super wealthy because
she saw something in me. She knew that
I'm worth investing and I'm not going to
waste that money and opportunity. So, I
can't mess up. That's one and I think
now that I've become somewhat a public
figure and a single mom, like I want the
world to see that you can thrive and
like leave the marriage that's not
working for you, especially women in
Korea. I feel like I see so many
instances where they're scared to leave
because oh, what if I can't find love
again or what if I can't become
independent financially or I if I'm not
a good mom. So, I feel like I need to be
that role model and an example for those
who are considering and who are not in a
good place. Um, I want to give them hope
that it's possible. It's not perfect.
I'm still figuring things out, but you
can try.
>> You are an excellent role model. Do you
have any tips for women that maybe want
to jump-start their career?
>> Oh, there's so many tips. I would say
impress everybody you meet along the
way. A lot of people, especially when
they're working for a very small company
or working with um junior people, they
think that oh, I'm never going to see
them again or I'm too good for them. So,
they don't put in their full selves.
But, I've seen so many instances where
like this one startup I worked at right
after college, the chief technology
officer, CTO, ended up becoming a
director at Meta. He's the one that
referred me to Meta.
But if I had this mindset of like, "Oh,
this company is so small. I'm only
working there because of visa issues." I
would not have had that opportunity. And
I'm not very good at this myself and I
need to work on it, but like
pleasantries are, "Oh, how was your
weekend?" Like I'm not good at it. I am
working on it, but um just, you know,
treating people with respect and being a
good partner. Not just because this
person can give you something
immediately, but the industry is so
small. You're going to run into them.
And the other thing is always negotiate
whenever you are going through an
interview process. A lot of women,
especially, they have limiting beliefs
about themselves and they don't know how
to ask for more. But remember, a
mediocre white man would be asking for
more for the same position you have. And
how pissed would you be if you realize
your peer, who may have fewer years of
experience, not as hard working or
whatever, is getting paid more because
they asked for more? That's actually not
good for the company for you to be
pissed off and less motivated as a
result because you didn't negotiate.
They expect you to negotiate, so it's
part of the job. So if you're showing
them, "I'm just going to take the first
offer," you're telling them you're not
going to be very good at your job. Like
I want someone who's going to be
fighting tooth and nail to whatever
negotiation, whatever contract that
they're reviewing. So that's actually a
good thing that you're showing. You're
showing your capabilities. The worst
thing is they could say no or they could
give you something else or they give you
smaller bump than you want. But not
asking for more is never a good idea.
>> That's a good point. I think a lot of
people are often scared to negotiate,
but like you said, the worst they can
say is no. So
>> Yeah, you already made it that far.
Finding a new candidate, that's so much
money and time that they have to spend
on their end. So they're going to give
it to you. Especially if your interview
process included directors and VPs and
their hours are like expensive. So
they're not going to say no because you
asked for a few more thousands of
dollars.
>> Very true. So you're running your own
businesses, you also have a family,
you're a mom. How do you balance all of
that and what are maybe some like
misconceptions that people have about
like working moms?
>> Mhm. I think especially being a mom, a
lot of moms and I've seen this with
Korean moms more so is that they feel
like they have to do everything and
that's what being a good mom looks like.
You have to be the one to chop the
vegetables and cook everything and pick
up the kids and do everything.
>> Mhm.
>> But if you're tired and exhausted when
you're with the child and you don't give
them attention then that's actually much
worse. So, I would say be okay with not
being perfect and then give your kids
chores. So, my son's been showering
himself since he was three. He does
everything in the morning. So, when I'm
packing him lunch, he wakes up, brushes
teeth, gets dressed and does everything
and comes out. So, try to not be the one
to check in on them all the time.
>> Mhm.
>> Because you're actually robbing them of
every little opportunity to build
confidence and make mistakes. So, don't
be that parent and it's actually less
work for you over time and you're
actually building a much stronger
resilient child.
>> It's a win-win. They get more
independent and then you get to spend
more quality time with them. So,
>> Yeah. First of all, ask for more,
interview at other places to make more
money in the first place. Always think
about that and then with the additional
income, try to hire help like to fold
laundry or pick up kids if you don't
have time, run errands, like whatever it
might be, try to hire help that does not
need to be you.
>> Got you.
>> So, I have ADHD. In Korea growing up,
everyone's like you're so distracted all
the time. Like
but actually don't give up. That's your
superpower, you know? ADHD means like I
have lots of interest but then things
that I'm interested in I go really deep
and I get obsessed with it. You know, I
think in the age of AI like all these
service roles like lawyer, it's just all
going to get taken over by AI. So, now
your superpower is your creativity and
having big dreams,
>> Mhm.
>> Not having limiting beliefs. And
sometimes like, who am I to be doing the
those things? And like,
>> You're so funny.
>> [laughter]
>> You're so funny. You're so funny.
>> But it's just like the limiting belief
you have.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah, I just try to tell myself to not
have those beliefs.
>> those beliefs, for sure. Thank you so
much.
>> So, yeah, I I do have a book in Korean
called the running brand in marketing
era. I don't know if it's still within
top 10 bestseller in the
self-development section, but yeah, it
was bestseller for several weeks and
people have given me good reviews. It
does have a lot of things we discussed
and especially business English. [music]
How do you say one thing in a more
eloquent way?
>> Mhm.
>> So, I recommend you guys check that out.
[music]
>> Definitely. We'll share the link for
sure in the comments. So, definitely
check it out. Thank you so much for
coming today and sharing your story and
letting us ask you some questions.
Really appreciate it.
>> Yeah, thank you. Good luck with your
English journey.
>> Bye.